Departmental Records, 1973-2008
Smithsonian Institution Archives
Departmental Records
1973-2008
Smithsonian Institution Archives, Washington, D.C., osiaref@si.edu
National Museum of Natural History,Dept. of Botany
SI Records
5 cu. ft. (5 record storage boxes)
Accession 10-152
Descriptive Entry
This accession documents the professional collaborations of the National Museum of Natural History, Department of Botany, with numerous organizations-most notably the Association for Tropical Biology. Materials also include exhibition records, memoranda and correspondence. All records were created or maintained by W. John Kress.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following access terms. These are links to collections with related topics, persons or places.
Name
Kress, W. John; Association for Tropical Biology
Subject
Botany
Physical Characteristics of Materials in the Collection
Manuscripts
- Box 1
  - Folder 1 Marquis, Bob 1995-1997 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 2 Denslow Association for Tropical Biology (ATB) Information 1996-1998 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 3 Travel Award Winners, ATB 1999-2001 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 4 Travel Reimbursement 1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 5 ATB Finances 1998 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 6 ATB Key Papers Book 1998-2000 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 7 ATB T-shirts 1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 8 BioOne Electronic Licensing Agreement 2001 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 9 ATB Bloomington Meeting 2000 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 10 ATB Biotropica 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 11 ATB Alwyn Gentry Student Paper Awards 1995-1998 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 12 ATB Honorary Fellows 1984-1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 13 ATB Travel Awards 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 14 ATB JSTOR 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 15 ATB Council Meeting 1998 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 16 ATB General Correspondence 1998-2001 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 17 ATB Strategic Plan 1998 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 18 ATB The American Institute of Biological Sciences (AIBS) Affairs 1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 19 ATB Allen Press 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 20 ATB Biotropica 1997-1998 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 21 1999 Meeting and Beyond 1999-2003 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 22 ATB Catalogs, Services, etc. 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 23 ATB Abstracts, Tropinet, American Funds Group (AFG) 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 24 ATB Action! 1998 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 25 ATB Nominations and Awards 1998 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 26 J. Kress ATB 1997 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 27 ATB Correspondence/Tropinet 1997 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 28 ATB at International Botanical Congress (IBC) 1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 29 ATB Council Meeting in St. Louis 1999 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 30 Allen Press Proofs Biotropica 2001 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 31 ATB Annual Reports to Council 1986-1994 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 32 ATB Awards 1986-1996 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 33 ATB Ballots 1982-1997 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Folder 34 ATB By-Laws 1973-1996 (Box 1 of 5)
- Box 2
  - Folder 1 ATB Council Correspondence 1983-1998 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 2 ATB Forms, Addresses, Phone Numbers 1990-1991 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 3 ATB Associate Management Renewal Records 1994-1997 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 4 Biotropica Online Services 1997-1998 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 5 ATB Editor, Board of Editors (BOE) 1995-1998 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 6 Allen Press, Contract 1993-1998 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 7 ATB Evans 1994-1997 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 8 Evans Fund - Current 1996-1998 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 9 ATB Gratis Subscriptions 1996 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 10 ATB Home Page 1995-1998 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 11 U.S. Forest Service (USFS) Literacy Project Latin American Library Enhancement Project (LALEP) 1991-1992 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 12 ATB Organization for Tropical Studies (OTS) Meeting 1996-1997 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 13 ATB Meetings Plans 1991-1996 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 14 ATB Meetings 1979-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 15 Reprint Permissions 1991-1997 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 16 ATB Rhode Island 1995-1997 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 17 ATB San Diego 1995 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 18 Association for Tropical Biology and Conservation (ATBC) Name Change 2001- 2003 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 19 ATBC Aberdeen Meeting 2002-2003 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 20 Banquet 2003 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 21 Tropinet 2001 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 22 ATB Web 2002 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 23 ATB Discussion, Next Meeting Location 2001-2002 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 24 Biotropica, Allen Press, Budget 2001-2002 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 25 ATB Meeting 2002 Panama 2002 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 26 ATB Meeting 2001 Bangalore 2000-2001 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 27 Notes/Messages for John Kress 1998-2008 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Folder 28 Notes/Messages for John Kress 2002-2005 (Box 2 of 5)
- Box 3
  - Folder 1 ATB Retreat February 2002, 2001-2002 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 2 ATB Retreat Expenses 2002 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 3 Bangalore Trip July 2001, 2001 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 4 Research Priorities in Tropical Biology, No Date (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 5 ATB Council Materials Bangalore 2001 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 6 Ashoka Trust for Research in Ecology and the Environment 1999-2001 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 7 ATB Council Bangalore 2001 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 8 Electronic Biotropica/Meeting Minutes 2000-2001 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 9 Kress Correspondence, Messages, Notes 1998-1999 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 10 Kress Correspondence, Messages, Notes 1999-2000 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 11 Kress Correspondence, Messages, Notes 2001-2002 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 12 Kress Correspondence, Messages, Notes 1999-2004 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 13 Kress Correspondence, Messages, Notes 2004-2005 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 14 Vision Statement for the National Museum of Natural History (NMNH) Collections 2001 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 15 Draft Report of FY 2000 Collections Profiling Project 2000 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 16 Smithsonian Science Strategic Direction 2001 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 17 Global Environmental Alliance - China 2000 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 18 Kress Correspondence, Notes 2000 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 19 Kress Correspondence 2003 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 20 Botany 2002 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 21 Kress Miscellaneous Correspondence 2003-2004 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 22 Publications 2003-2004 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 23 Kress Notes 2002-2004 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Folder 24 Kress Miscellaneous 2001 (Box 3 of 5)
- Box 4
  - Folder 1 Unites States Botanical Gardens (USBG) Luncheon 2002 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 2 Caribbean Islands Project Overview 2001 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 3 Coalition for Excellence in Tropical Biology (CETroB) National Science Foundation (NSF) 2001 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 4 The Coalition for Excellence in Tropical Biology 2001 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 5 Islands in the Storm 2001 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 6 Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) for CETroB 2000 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 7 CETroB and World Wildlife Fund (WWF) Meeting 2001 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 8 CETroB Symposium 2000 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 9 CETroB Miami Meeting 1999 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 10 Mammals Hall 1998-2000 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 11 USBG Exhibits 1999-2001 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 12 USBG MOU Signing 2000 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 13 USBG MOU Signing NMNH Original 2000 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 14 CETroB 1999-2000 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 15 CETroB Miami, 1999 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 16 USBG 1999-2000 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 17 CETroB - Miami 1998 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 18 USBG 1998 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 19 Biology Exhibits 1997-1999 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 20 Biology Exhibits - Animal Hall 1998 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Folder 21 Biology Exhibits 1997 (Box 4 of 5)
- Box 5
  - Folder 1 Beyond Paradise Presentation 2004 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 2 Beyond Paradise Biotropica 2004 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 3 Beyond Paradise Brochures 2004 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 4 Beyond Paradise Science 2004 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 5 Beyond Paradise Press Release 2004 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 6 Beyond Paradise Articles and Draft Outline 2004 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 7 Beyond Paradise Plan of Action 2004 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 8 ATB Retreat II, 2001-2003 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 9 Beyond Paradise Aberdeen 2003 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 10 ATB White Paper Drafts (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 11 Sherwood Exhibit at National Museum of Natural History (NMNH) 2001-2002 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 12 Sherwood Exhibit Letters, Articles 2003 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 13 ATB Retreat 2001-2002 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 14 Sherwood Exhibit Press Preview 2001-2003 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Folder 15 ATB Priorities Workshop 2001-2002 (Box 5 of 5)